[Music]
[Applause]
There's a ton of research that's been
published lately showing that training a
muscle at longer lengths is superior to
training a muscle at shorter lengths in
terms of hypertrophy. So, the
evidence-based bros have taken this to
mean that exercises working in a short
position, like a hip thrust, suck and
exercises that work in a long length
position, like squats, are vastly
superior. There is no research showing
that squats are superior to hip thrusts
for glute growth. They're basing these
claims off of research pertaining to the
biceps, the triceps, the calves, the
quads, and the hamstrings. So, are the
glutes unique? Do they respond better to
short length position exercises? Or are
there physiological principles governing
all muscles and do all muscles respond
better to training them at longer
lengths? Time will tell. I want to show
you why these guys don't know what the
hell they're talking about. They will
tell you that there's zero torque at the
bottom of a hip thrust, but there is. In
fact, the hip extension torque in a hip
thrust is fairly consistent and it's
high throughout the whole range of
motion. You know what exercise does have
zero torque in the bottom position in
the lengthened position? Lateral raises
and bent over rear delt raises. Laterals
and bent over rear delts only work you
in the shortened position. In the
lengthened position, there's no torque.
But, they're not going after these delt
exercises. We have all these
evidence-based bros going after a hip
thrust while conveniently ignoring
concentration curls, lateral raises, pec
deck, and things of that nature. So, if
they really believed in what they say
that you should only perform exercises
that work you in a lengthened position,
then this is how you would do lateral
raises. You do them side lying like
this.
And this is how you would do rear delt
raises. You'd also do them side lying
like this.
Doing them this way maximizes tension in
the lengthened position and would
theoretically be superior to the
standard standing method. Give these a
try. You won't like them. They don't
feel natural. They feel silly compared
to the standing variation. You feel like
you're not even working the muscle
through much of a ROM. So, my guess is
that time will tell that hip thrusts are
superior for glute hypertrophy than
squats and lateral raises and bent over
rear delt raises superior to side lying
dumbbell laterals and rear delt raises.
In the meantime, let's see if these bros
are consistent with their attack on
exercise. Let's see if they go after the
lateral raise and the bent over rear
delt. If they don't, it can only mean
one thing that they're massively jealous
of the hip thrust success.